<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>BTUT</title>
        <description>Been There Undone That (or What To Do Until The Good Fairy Comes) - A guide to having a happier, more relaxed and productive life.</description>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/</link>
        <atom:link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <pubDate>Thu, 04 Aug 2022 16:04:35 -0400</pubDate>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 04 Aug 2022 16:04:35 -0400</lastBuildDate>
        <generator>Jekyll v4.2.2</generator>
        
            <item>
                <title>Perfection vs. Excellence</title>
                <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Don’t let the perfect be the enemy of the good.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Voltaire&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before going further, let me acknowledge a huge positive aspect of the compulsive perfectionist’s attitude: great things have been accomplished by perfectionists and those with a compulsive desire to succeed!  The maniacal pursuit of a goal with little or no consideration of other factors and consequences, along with an indominable will to succeed has produced many of the great discoveries, advances, and accomplishments we revere and appreciate so much.  Some artists, musicians, scientists, athletes, and businessmen have this drive and have accounted for many incredible advances in our lives.   Even on a personal basis, I would credit a good portion of what I achieved in life to the drive and determination that came along with my attempt to achieve perfection.  You can even look at the poem “If” by Rudyard Kipling as an anthem for the grit and determination that the dive for perfection requires.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My desire for perfectionism began with the influence of my mother and father. I tried to get more comfort, love and affection from them, at home or in school, and I did this by trying to be a perfect son for them. Not giving them a reason to be disappointed in me resulted in praise, status, etc. in school, at work and in life in general. So it was reinforced. This caused me to get a bit out of control and I began an exercise regime to achieve some control in my life when I felt like I did not have any. I adopted some of these life goals: be successful in school and in my career, provide well for my family, uphold my end of the deal that I made with life which was to work hard, succeed, and then be able to enjoy the benefits thereof. I also wanted to do well, have a good sense of humor, be kind to others, etc. as a way of making friends as well as having help available if a high anxiety or panic attack struck and help was needed.
I am not sure who came up with the idea that “you do less than you ought to do unless you do all that you’re capable of doing;” but you must admit that it is a catchy phrase, right?  And so inspiring too!  So is my dad’s favorite “If it is worth doing, it’s worth doing well!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Always give 100% unless you’re donating blood.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Bad Idea T-Shirts&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This desire for perfection is easiest to see in top athletes, coaches, or the Steve Jobs of the world, who drive themselves and those around them to achieve a goal. In his weekly articles in the New Orleans Times-Picayune, Mackie Shilstone, fitness consultant to many high profile professional athletes, frequently refers to their “drive, determination, preparation, commitment to excellence, unyielding drive to perfection, and perseverance.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But of course, there is that tiny problem which I have been wrestling with for six or seven decades:  the compulsive pursuit of perfection can screw up the rest of your life! It can kill you, drive you crazy, and/or create a stress level which is impossible to deal with. It will “inspire” you to do as much as you can but if you really follow this thinking literally, it is impossible to achieve. It definitely will “inspire” you to do as much as you can, but to what ultimate end? It doesn’t produce warmth, peace, relaxation, good relationships, or a generally happy life.  At least that was my experience and my conclusion; and I have read a number of books that confirm this – both from a psychological as well as biological point of view.&lt;br /&gt;
I tend to be a very literal guy in many ways, so my ultimate conclusion is to take perfectionism with a large grain of salt, or realism, and that’s why I am a strong proponent of excellentism as opposed to perfectionism! Like everything else in life, the emphasis you put on the quality of your effort is a choice you make as to the life you want to lead. You could say there is a continuum between lackadaisical living on the left to balance (excellence) in the middle to perfectionism on the right end. It is up to you to decide where to set the button on the sliding control (think of the adjustments on a sound board with all those sliding controls).  There isn’t any preordained perfect setting – it is up to you; and you make the decision for yourself. You do this consciously or unconsciously, but it behooves you to know the tradeoffs!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While I am speaking about perfectionism, but the very same things can be said about the excessive need to control or having unhealthy compulsions.  When you think about it, those terms are just forms of perfectionism from a layman’s point of view.  This is an important point, but for the sake of brevity (of which I am rarely accused!) I have lumped them together with perfectionism.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you need things to be perfect, you are going to want to control them.  Maybe you think you have to do everything because no one else will do it “right” or do it “your way….”  Delegation is not likely to be your strong suit.  Also, you are going to want to control the environment to try to keep it all together.  It seems to me that sooner or later this is going to negatively impact your inter-personal relationships and other important aspects of life. And when you try to control everything, you enjoy nothing.  Instead, your goal might be to relax, breathe a little, let go, and just live. Slide that adjustment button more towards “balanced.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My point here is to stand down, relaxing from perfectionism to excellentism.  A full-fledged perfectionist may resist this at first due to being uncomfortable with anything other than perfection as a goal, and the worry that any slight relaxing will just be the first step on the slippery slope leading to degradation or being only average.  But not so.  There is little if any chance that a one-time perfectionist will become a slouch.  It almost can’t happen.  If you buy into the theory that there are two kinds of people, racehorses and turtles (each perfect in their own way), even if the one-time racehorse learns to relax at times, he will still be a racehorse, just one that is happier, more productive, smells the flowers more often  and one which may well probably win more races overall and in the long run. Granted if you try to make a race horse out of a turtle, you will kill it; and if you try to make a turtle out of a race horse, the same outcome may occur. But I am not talking about such a drastic transformation, just an adjustment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/06-2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Tree&quot; /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Photo by &lt;a href=&quot;https://unsplash.com/photos/_uqDYFkrmLM&quot;&gt;Angela Pham&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;a href=&quot;https://unsplash.com/&quot;&gt;Unsplash&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                <pubDate>Wed, 03 Aug 2022 08:01:35 -0400</pubDate>
                <link>http://localhost:4000/book-excerpt-3</link>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/book-excerpt-3</guid>
                
                <category>lifestyle</category>
                
                <category>help</category>
                
                <category>story</category>
                
                
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Be You</title>
                <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Be yourself; everyone else is already taken!&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Attributed to Oscar Wilde&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Be yourself! This sounds easy in one sense but can be quite a challenge if you have a poor self-image and don’t especially like the person you think you really are.  Many people avoid thinking about who they are because it is not a pleasing image for them.  You may get used to playing a part to avoid showing your true self to others.  The truth is that, if you will relax and try to get in touch with how magnificent you really are, you can begin to improve your self-image and begin to love who you are.  If you need some tweaking and want to change certain things about yourself, get busy and do it.  And if you need help in achieving this, many resources exist for you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Have the courage to follow your heart and intuition. They somehow know what you truly want to become.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Do not sublimate or “sell out” your true self to a greater degree than is acceptable to you in the spirit of compromise and love.  Each person’s level of acceptance is different, but the body and mind have ways of telling you if you have gone too far – they are called anxiety, depression, panic attacks, nightmares, etc.  All of these discomforts are horrible to experience, but, more importantly, they do act as a warning system for your mind and body that you may be sublimating yourself too much, especially if you view yourself as needy.
Being yourself involves developing a consistency among the things you say, what you think, and what you do.  This may sound rather simple, but only if you have not tried it!  And it certainly is not easy at first.  Yet it is quite freeing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Life is short; don’t waste yours by living someone else’s.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Do you ever feel “I don’t think I’m the right person to be leading my life?” If you do not show the real you, you can never be loved for who you are. You are not letting anyone see the real you if you feel you need to hide or lie to be loved. Be honest with others.  Your real self will come out at times, one way or another.  You cannot stuff away your true feelings without having it affect your actions and statements in some way. This is similar to a jack in the box, a water balloon, or a drop of mercury.  When you push in one place, it pokes out in another.  Your mind and your real beliefs are very tough to fool, and often the signals of anxiety or fear, for example, are there because your mind senses conflict.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Your time is limited, so don’t waste it living someone else’s life. Don’t be trapped by dogma—which is living with the results of other people’s thinking. Don’t let the noise of others’ opinions drown out your own inner voice. And most important, have the courage to follow your heart and intuition.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Steve Jobs&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is perfectly okay to be different, yourself.  BUT, have some fun, do things other would not, may not do.  Fun and liberating to be a little different.  At the end of the day, not many things are that important.  Ask yourself “How bad is it really?  Who really cares?”  If you get the right answers back, consider going for it.  If you have a bit of an imp or a little devil inside, let him out sometimes. Nothing really bad – immoral, illegal, or fattening; don’t lie and certainly never hurt anyone else.  There is a ton of room within which most of us can work and have a lot of flexibility with which to express ourselves.  Here are some examples of things I have done that I relish the memories of:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Being nice to strangers by offering help.  For instance, help an elderly person struggling with groceries.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Take pictures of families instead of one of them being excluded to take the picture.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Helping friends after an operation, having emotional issues, etc.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Encouraged our son the walk with his twin sister in her graduation ceremony at a different university a week after he graduated.  No one else knew, no one cared and he too his own favorite memories from their graduations.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Try something you are really bad at just because it is fun to do. For me, this includes doing yoga; God never really intended for me to do yoga.  Also, I joined a couple of exercise classes with nothing but ladies, 10-20 per session, a few of whom can kick my butt.  Most men shy away from these and never continue to attend after tying once or twice.  But it has been fun and I’ve added many friends.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Be who God created you to be and you will set the world on fire&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;cite&gt;St. Catherine of Siena&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A few years ago my older brother and I decided to take a trip together and since we are both computer and gadget enthusiasts, we thought it would be cool to go to the Consumer Electronics Show in Las Vegas.  One small problem however, was that it is open only to people in that industry, and TECHNICALLY we did not qualify.  Undaunted by that minor little hurdle, we resurrected the H &amp;amp; H Home Fix-It Service which we ran about 60 years earlier when our parents encouraged us to go door to door offering to do such critical jobs around the home as rewiring lamps and adjusting clamps on ladies’ earrings.  I think our total summer revenue was around $15 and didn’t cover the cost of the cards our parents had printed for us to leave at people’s homes.  He had worked in the computer industry for years and we had both helped others with computer issues.  We used this to rename our “company” the H &amp;amp; H Computer Consulting Service with a company motto and official business cards.  I was prepared to actually set up a dummy corporation but it turned out that submitting the business cards was all that was required.  So for $30, we were good to go and had a terrific time.  During the activities in Vegas, I also met Walt Mossberg who was THE prominent Wall Street Journal electronics columnist at the time.  I will never forget that as I saw him window shopping and went over to him and introduced myself and had a chance to tell him how very much I enjoyed and relied on his work.  This was a stretch for us both, but it is a good example of the “Who cares?  Did it hurt anyone; and is it immoral, illegal, or fattening?”  I think we both enjoyed the whole experience, partly because it was a little edgy for us both; but I did notice that the world did not stop spinning and the sun did continue to come up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have mentioned some specific activities above that I have found helpful, but a slightly different idea is for you to do something, anything YOU find enjoyable.  Making room in your schedule for enjoyable activities that you look forward to can also help.  This could be anything from a relaxing cup of coffee, to visiting with a friend, or going to see a movie or watching a 30 minute TV show. Just try to take a little time to relax.  The following are strategies I use to help me achieve these goals:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For my mind:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Working to identify demons and all roadblocks that hinder my being the happy and productive, helpful person I want to be.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Employing strategies to live in a way that nurtures me, helps me be happy and peaceful, and makes me a better person who can help others.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For my body:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;live a healthy live&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;no smoking&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;no drinking&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;eat in a healthy manner&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;low fats&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;high protein&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;juices&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;low sugar&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;low salt&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;no butter&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;very little dressings&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;virtually no sauces&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;working on eating more slowly, putting fork down between bites&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;get good, restful, restorative sleep&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;get  good strength and cardio exercise every week; 3-5   1 hour sessions each week&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For my spirit:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;continue my spiritual quest&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;church with my family and/or friends&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;further investigation, reading, pondering of many different spiritual matters&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;stay in touch with a spiritual advisor and discuss, read things that come up&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Strategies such as these require commitment and diligence. But the strategy of just being as honest as you possibly can as much of the time as possible is the simplest and best way of achieving the amazing results you will find in being YOU!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/06-1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Mountains&quot; /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Photo by &lt;a href=&quot;https://unsplash.com/photos/2IWxOWMVB6w&quot;&gt;Devon Hawkins&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;a href=&quot;https://unsplash.com/&quot;&gt;Unsplash&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                <pubDate>Wed, 03 Aug 2022 08:01:35 -0400</pubDate>
                <link>http://localhost:4000/book-excerpt-2</link>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/book-excerpt-2</guid>
                
                <category>chapter</category>
                
                <category>story</category>
                
                <category>help</category>
                
                
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Give, Do for Others</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;To help yourself, help others.  It works. Many people get through tragedies, terrible grief or loss, bad news, etc. by helping others. There are countless things which can be done, and I’m sure you have heard many stories of people surviving unspeakable grief and sorrow by reaching out to help others who may also be in pain. Or if you prefer a more anonymous approach you could do something like donating blood.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The important thing is to do something, anything … avoid being stuck.   Doing something for or with others gets you out of your head, and it can help your sense of empathy and gratitude.
As I was writing this, I watched the 15th anniversary special on the 9-11-01 terrorist attack and during the program a married couple discussed how they were able to cope with the incomprehensible pain and unspeakable grief they had experienced in losing an adult son on that day.  They had started a foundation in his name which was doing good works for others and they said quite clearly that “if you want to feel better, go help someone.”  If this advice helped them, I think it would help just about anyone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, I once had an unusual experience in Mobile, Ala. Early in my professional career – when I was in my 20’s − I was wandering around town at 3-4 AM, far too anxious to sleep.  A man approached and asked for the directions to the bus station.  Incredibly, I was able to supply this information.  He went on his way and I experienced an almost miraculous purging of anxiety.  I was instantly healed, so to speak; and I went back to the hotel and immediately went to sleep.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was amazing, both for the curative effect as well another feature.  Those who know me will find this story very unusual since I have a well-deserved reputation for never knowing where things are or how to get to places.  This story IS true, however, although I have considered that the man I helped may, to this day, still be looking for the bus station! Actually, my directional difficulties are so bad that when I was 15 and getting my driver’s license, the family joke was that I would not be allowed to drive in fear of my not being able to ever find my way home.  Suffice it to say that GPS is still a Godsend for me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/15-1.jpg#wide&quot; alt=&quot;River&quot; /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Photo by &lt;a href=&quot;https://unsplash.com/photos/_w7CkrJdn1Q&quot;&gt;Jeroen Bendeler&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;a href=&quot;https://unsplash.com/&quot;&gt;Unsplash&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
                <pubDate>Wed, 03 Aug 2022 08:01:35 -0400</pubDate>
                <link>http://localhost:4000/book-excerpt-1</link>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/book-excerpt-1</guid>
                
                <category>chapter</category>
                
                <category>story</category>
                
                <category>help</category>
                
                
            </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>