<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>BTUT</title>
        <description>Been There Undone That (or What To Do Until The Good Fairy Comes) - A guide to having a happier, more relaxed and productive life.</description>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/</link>
        <atom:link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <pubDate>Thu, 04 Aug 2022 10:10:32 -0400</pubDate>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 04 Aug 2022 10:10:32 -0400</lastBuildDate>
        <generator>Jekyll v4.2.2</generator>
        
            <item>
                <title>Book Excerpt 3</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;TEXT TEXT TEXT&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/06-2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Tree&quot; /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Photo by &lt;a href=&quot;https://unsplash.com/photos/_uqDYFkrmLM&quot;&gt;Angela Pham&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;a href=&quot;https://unsplash.com/&quot;&gt;Unsplash&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                <pubDate>Wed, 03 Aug 2022 08:01:35 -0400</pubDate>
                <link>http://localhost:4000/book-excerpt-3</link>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/book-excerpt-3</guid>
                
                <category>lifestyle</category>
                
                <category>travel</category>
                
                <category>story</category>
                
                
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Book Excerpt 2</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;TEXT TEXT TEXT&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/06-1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Mountains&quot; /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Photo by &lt;a href=&quot;https://unsplash.com/photos/2IWxOWMVB6w&quot;&gt;Devon Hawkins&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;a href=&quot;https://unsplash.com/&quot;&gt;Unsplash&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                <pubDate>Wed, 03 Aug 2022 08:01:35 -0400</pubDate>
                <link>http://localhost:4000/book-excerpt-2</link>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/book-excerpt-2</guid>
                
                <category>chapter</category>
                
                <category>story</category>
                
                <category>help</category>
                
                
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Give, Do for Others</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;To help yourself, help others.  It works. Many people get through tragedies, terrible grief or loss, bad news, etc. by helping others. There are countless things which can be done, and I’m sure you have heard many stories of people surviving unspeakable grief and sorrow by reaching out to help others who may also be in pain. Or if you prefer a more anonymous approach you could do something like donating blood.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The important thing is to do something, anything … avoid being stuck.   Doing something for or with others gets you out of your head, and it can help your sense of empathy and gratitude.
As I was writing this, I watched the 15th anniversary special on the 9-11-01 terrorist attack and during the program a married couple discussed how they were able to cope with the incomprehensible pain and unspeakable grief they had experienced in losing an adult son on that day.  They had started a foundation in his name which was doing good works for others and they said quite clearly that “if you want to feel better, go help someone.”  If this advice helped them, I think it would help just about anyone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, I once had an unusual experience in Mobile, Ala. Early in my professional career – when I was in my 20’s − I was wandering around town at 3-4 AM, far too anxious to sleep.  A man approached and asked for the directions to the bus station.  Incredibly, I was able to supply this information.  He went on his way and I experienced an almost miraculous purging of anxiety.  I was instantly healed, so to speak; and I went back to the hotel and immediately went to sleep.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was amazing, both for the curative effect as well another feature.  Those who know me will find this story very unusual since I have a well-deserved reputation for never knowing where things are or how to get to places.  This story IS true, however, although I have considered that the man I helped may, to this day, still be looking for the bus station! Actually, my directional difficulties are so bad that when I was 15 and getting my driver’s license, the family joke was that I would not be allowed to drive in fear of my not being able to ever find my way home.  Suffice it to say that GPS is still a Godsend for me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/15-1.jpg#wide&quot; alt=&quot;River&quot; /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Photo by &lt;a href=&quot;https://unsplash.com/photos/_w7CkrJdn1Q&quot;&gt;Jeroen Bendeler&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;a href=&quot;https://unsplash.com/&quot;&gt;Unsplash&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
                <pubDate>Wed, 03 Aug 2022 08:01:35 -0400</pubDate>
                <link>http://localhost:4000/book-excerpt-1</link>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/book-excerpt-1</guid>
                
                <category>chapter</category>
                
                <category>story</category>
                
                <category>help</category>
                
                
            </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>